# Karthika Baiju

As a Digital Product Designer, I excel in crafting impactful experiences and reimagining human-technology interaction. With 2.5 years of UX and digital product design experience, combined with 4+ years in the tech industry, I specialize in interaction, visual, and interface design. My unique background in both design and engineering allows me to bridge the gap between these two worlds effectively.

# **EXPERIENCE**

# Designer, Blum Center - UC Berkeley

Berkeley, Sep 2022 - Present

- Managed all facets of website usability for UC Berkeley Blum Center through user testing, revisions, and user flow redesign, resulting in improved navigation and overall user experience.
- Collaborated closely with Center's leadership to understand their needs and designing a user-friendly website that effectively communicated the Center's mission and goals to its audience.
- Aligned design recommendations with industry standards and organizational goals, optimizing user experience and driving increased engagement, satisfaction, and conversion rates.

### Product Designer, Rumifico - HP

Berkeley, Aug 2022 - Dec 2022

- Lead user research and analysis, journey mapping, early stage prototyping in Figma, testing and wireframe creation resulting in an user centered product.
- Designed human-centered soluwtion for students to receive messages from parents without constant phone usage, resulting in improved communication and convenience, with 70% of users expressing interest in adoption.

# Software Engineer, Microsoft

Hyderabad, Sep 2018 - July 2022

- Played a pivotal role as an engineer and UX designer, contributing to the development of a platform for on-site improving resource tracking and progress monitoring, resulting in accelerated Azure data center construction globally.
- Led UX design process, achieving 20% performance boost by conducting research, ideation, wireframing, visual design, and efficient handoff.
- Spearheaded design of the critical Test Script Management module, enabling users to create and execute equipment tests efficiently, further enhancing productivity and efficiency on site.
- Gained experience in cross-functional collaboration, and user-centered design, partnering with diverse teams to meet project goals.

## UX Designer, Vet's Pocket - Freelance

Hyderabad, Sept 2020 - Nov 2021

- Developed a mobile app for field veterinarians, optimizing business processes such as appointment scheduling, patient record keeping, billing, and reporting resulting in 2-3 hours saved weekly.
- Led user-centered testing and prototyping, with a focus on in-depth user research through interviews, card sorting, and experience mapping.
- Established and maintained design system to guide design and development of the application, ensuring unified experience.

# **EDUCATION**

University of California, Berkeley Master of Design, Human-Computer Interaction, Dec 2023

Covt. Model Engineering College, Kochi (Cochin University of Science and Technology) B.Tech Electronics and Communication, June 2018

# SKILLS

## Design Skills

Storyboarding, Synthesizing, Wireframing, Rapid Prototyping, High-fidelity Prototypes, Human Computer Interaction Research, User Experience Design, Visual Design, Interaction Design, Design Systems

#### Design Tools

Figma, Sketch, Laser Cutting, Fusion 360, 3D Printing, Blender, Adobe Creative Suite

#### User Research

Usability Testing, Contextual Interview, Card Sorting, Qualitative Analysis

### Programming

C#, C++, HTML + CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript, Python, Unity, Processing, P5.js

# **AWARDS**

**Figma Config Scholar, 2023** Figma

# MDes Distinguished Scholar Award,

University of California, Berkeley

Grace Hopper India Conference Student Scholar, 2017 AnitaB.org